hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft as you
can see i've made a little bit of
progress today i got back from my trip
just yesterday so i am very behind on
many many things i have done a little
bit of progress today so there is
something going on i have fixed the
redstone behind here thank you to
everyone that helped me out with that i
was really struggling so now i'm going
to replace this with a button so there
we go we have the button installed this
redstone now works i mean it's very very
basic stuff but it works and that's the
main thing we're gonna replant these
potatoes because we're actually
collecting a lot of these for trading
with the villages and i'm gonna explain
that a little bit later on because one
of the first things that we're gonna do
today
is buy a season pass to a shop
so that's exactly what we're gonna go
and do now we're gonna go and buy that
pass now that the potatoes are growing
again we're just gonna shift over all of
these potatoes into my shulker box but
before we head off to the shop i just
want to show you the little bit of
progress that i made you can see
i have actually opted to start doing
things underneath the platform
which is actually much easier than it
might seem if we go down
as long as i have the conduit power
which is by squidward's house over there
i should be able to one see like so
and i should be able to swim and
everything else so it's basically like a
really slow way of flying therefore it's
actually easier to build underwater than
i initially thought so basically what
i'm gonna do is
i think i'm gonna do this layer first
clearing out the water is not a priority
but
it will give me a better idea of what
this is going to look like overall so
you can kind of see that i've made these
gray cyan terracotta edge all the way
down to the bottom where they connect
and it's a little bit odd i'm really
really not sure how this is going to end
up looking
but i have faith in the design
nonetheless in the time that i've been
gone
scar
has literally built an entire new island
unbelievable with a bit of a mayan
temple in there as well
the man is crazy so we're going to go
and buy this pass and i'm going to
explain how this all works and why i'm
even doing this in the first place hello
hey green how you doing man not bad oh i
didn't oh
i was gonna buy the the pass from me i
didn't actually bring any money if you
can't end a chest somewhere
i do i do oh it's right there okay so
how much is this
it's 32 diamonds cool half a snack as
they say well it was 25 at the beginning
of the season
i yeah and then and then i had a lot of
feedback from you know from customers
that wanted to pay more huh oh yeah yeah
no the viewers thought i was actually
under selling this place because it's
it's actually pretty amazing inside to
be honest so
are you gonna be worth the diamonds
you're gonna have to all right i'll i'll
fork it over there you go half a stack i
feel like i've been thoroughly scammed
but i don't think i have so this isn't
the pass now how do i actually get in
yeah that's the that's the secret man
it's pretty pretty tricky here but you
see this right here this dot of the eye
just toss your book out there and that's
going to open the door for you you
collect it on the way in
you're imagining right you're a magic
man
i do a little bit of redstone you know
so
some of my viewers are minecraft experts
some of them aren't so can you give a
brief explanation of how this works
with the whole trading thing yeah just
for those that don't don't understand me
included
oh okay i got you i got you so yeah i
got a bunch of different librarian
villagers in here and basically what
they'll trade is enchanted books for
uh basically emeralds and a book so
you're gonna need to kind of get some
emeralds and i have a way to do that as
well
a lot of good ways to do it is with
farmers so i have a few farmers in the
corners here you could trade crops which
are pretty easy to get right well that's
good because i brought some potatoes
pretty good yeah so you could trade
those potatoes with the farmers grab
yourself some emeralds um i don't have
books in here for sale yet but uh you
know those are easy to make it's paper
and leather you bring your own books and
you can go to each one of these guys and
i have signs with the the costs of
basically so mending for 10 emeralds in
one book and you can buy a mending book
from him and apply that to your gear and
then basically your diamond gear should
last you all season if you don't you
know die in lava which you would never
do right now yeah i've never died in
this game never
not even once
okay so this is just a series of trading
that needs to happen so that i can get
the good stuff on my gear
right yeah okay and if you uh if you run
out of crops here i do have what we call
micro transactions in the back okay so
you're trying to get even more money out
of us
can i can i ask how much how many
diamonds you make out of this um
let's see you're probably like the 10th
hermit so at least 320 plus micro chance
actually we'll call it we'll call 350. i
probably made 350 diamonds on this place
so far i've got like half a stack of
diamonds last time i've racked through
mine really quick
i've been i've been good about
recirculating these diamonds though so
oh there you go that was your first
trade with a villager ever i know yeah
it literally is ever
oh
this is this is a bit too much for me
i've never ever dealt with any of this
before
all right well thank you very much i'm
gonna have to go and grab my book and
stuff but yeah this is gonna this is
gonna help me out with all of the
the enchanting that i need to do
i mean i've been very unlucky all of my
diamond gear just has fire protection
and that's it uh there there is a
another book shop there is another book
shop if you didn't know
i do know uh i did i actually checked
that out a little bit ago and in fact
right underneath it's right underneath
your shop
it in fact it is
he's undercutting you a bit
for sure i went in here i went in here
and in my professional opinion yeah
these prices are just too much they're
just changed
oh yeah i mean he wants like 15 diamonds
for mending you just paid me 32 and you
can have unlimited mending books for the
rest of the season so
you know what i mean in here you once
you buy three you're already over what
you paid me so
yeah you're gonna get a lot more from me
so i'm not too worried about this
business i see what he's doing
[Laughter]
oh i got one other thing i got one thing
i want to show you yeah is this another
oh is this another thing where i can
waste my money
this is i loot right you throw in one
block of diamond and you're gonna get an
eye loop box it's a shulker box full of
goodies
but it's it's like rubbish in there
right
actually to be honest right now it's
pretty good stuff oh don't do this to me
you know i'm a curious guy
there's a really good chance you're
gonna get your diamond back and then
some all right right now
yeah
all right i'll do it
i'm
get in early if you want a good chance
are you gonna do it right now i'm gonna
try it i'm gonna try you've tempted me
you've okay persuaded me that i'm i'm a
poor man i'm like buying my lottery
ticket with my last dollar okay i gotta
tell you i'm i'm crossing my fingers for
you i really want to hear you guys i'm
hoping you get good stuff well i get to
keep the
keep the joker box too so right there
that's a good deal i mean that's usually
six diamonds by itself if this is full
of coal
we're gonna fall out
oh
no look at that
gold man you got your diamond block back
is this one of the best ones
yeah that's one of the best ones there's
only a few that had a diamond block in
there so you got your money back plus
some so see i thought this was a scam
no way man oh my goodness
you're welcome to come back as much as
you want now i know this game i know
this game i know this game the first one
is going to be full of good stuff and
then it's going to be full of like coal
and rubbish
no never oh yeah should we should we bet
should we bet what's in this one
okay all right
not not so good but not actually not too
bad not as look there's a mending book
already in there for you so that's
pretty good that's actually really good
diamond's back no you're getting me
addicted to this i'm leaving i'm cashing
out
okay i'm catching up
before this gets out of hand
quit while you're ahead yeah i think
i've done pretty well
oh yeah definitely
i'm scared of that box i'm doing
business with you
thanks a lot impulse cheers alright see
you later
so that was pretty good we we got away
with a decent amount of stuff
building this space isn't going to get
me any diamonds
whatsoever we really need
something special something
unique
and so i think it's time that we start
working on green's shop
so i really want to get mending on this
asap and because i was given a mending
book in that thing what what
what
how did i get poisoned
excuse me
excu what
okay
i got poisoned just
what the heck
what have they done here
oh
someone's put a puffer fish
in my boat
someone's put a puffer fish in my boat
i can't i can't get past him oh my
goodness
am i gonna die from this
i have to go round they must have no
they knew i was gonna pass through there
okay i tell you what this guy's kind of
cute wait there we go i got an
achievement tactical fishing we have a
bucket of pufferfish well i've been
totally totally sidetracked now because
this guy's just this guy is so cute
this guy is so cute we're actually gonna
go and do something with him right now
i learned a really really cool trick the
other day so all you need is a bunch of
staircases and slabs and that's
basically it so we're going to make a
little
square here we're going to go up quite a
few blocks to create a gap between two
layers and we're going to do the same
thing exactly the same thing but
mirrored upside down and then you've got
yourself a little sandwich and then
you've got to fill in the water
here
first so every single block is saturated
with water and there we go it's all
filled in there's not a single block
that is missing and then if we add water
here it falls down and then doesn't
spill anywhere so we can basically take
it from the bottom and put it on every
single one at the top and it should
just fall straight downwards because it
thinks that this is a source block and
therefore doesn't actually need to go
anywhere so what we've actually got if
you hadn't worked it out
is we have
a borderless aquarium so there's no need
to put glass to stop it falling
everywhere we've got a really clean
design for an aquarium so there we have
it our little aquarium so there we have
it our little aquarium there is a slight
problem with this in the fact that
if you put more than one fish in here
they will push each other out and fall
and well yeah they won't they won't
survive but we can put one little fish
in here and he will happily float about
and shouldn't leave the confines of this
very cool aquarium so we're going to
officially name him pufferfish paul
there we go hello paul
welcome to the family so
one little prank has turned into one
little pet and he's so cute so we're
gonna keep paul forever forever and ever
and ever he's gonna live in here for the
time being and we'll look after him for
as long as we can
welcome paul and whoever did that thank
you for the pet that was very nice of
you also don't i'm back at the shop but
don't you think it's a little bit
questionable that the modern sign
looks
extremely like the prehistoric sign that
you find in roller coaster tycoon too
hmm a bit weird
now i want to go and take a quick look
at mumbo's base because i know he's been
working on
well
essentially the death star
look at this
so i've obviously been away for a week
so i haven't seen the progress being
made by everyone
this is mental and it looks like
we have been using pretty much the same
blocks a lot of glass wait a minute
this is water
why is he got water here is there a
reason
why would he have water here surely that
would make it
harder to get around
not sure
but this is so cool
i'm loving this i can't wait to see i
don't know whether he's going to fill
the whole thing in and basically
actually have have a sphere but it
doesn't seem so at the moment i'm really
interested to see what he does kind of
want to see what's going on down here
has anything changed what's going on
here
how do i get in
his base has been flooded
what
his base has been totally flooded and
it's full of seagrass
what on earth uh
your front door's missing oh my goodness
okay so he's got an entirely new
entrance
oh this is so cool
what a mess
i'm here to fix the leak
mumbo's got a weird phantom block thing
there's a couple of bits here that we
just can't fix no matter what you place
it doesn't want to work even if you
place a piston and power it it doesn't
doesn't do anything
this is so weird
either way
i'm just gonna put a few fans on his i
guess
i guess i'm a big mumbo fan because i'm
putting fans all over the place
so we're just gonna put a little bit of
color in here
and maybe just a tiny bit of purple
so it scales turned up to fix it
whatever was wrong
can you do it
doesn't look like it
he's trying exactly what i did but it
doesn't seem to work
how many minecrafters does it take to
fix a block of air
look at this odd scene going on this
girl's just sitting inside the phantom
block mumbo's just jumping around
what is going on in here
so a few waterlogged blocks a couple of
staircases
and we've got ourselves a nice looking
area but there's nothing we can do
to fix this apparently
let's head on back to the base
where we can continue doing some work
okay so i took a bit of time to prepare
for everything because i i went to go
and start making the pickle shop and i
suddenly realized i was woefully
unprepared so i've spent hours and i
mean hours collecting stuff i've got
packed ice ice
a bunch of white concrete powder now
and some potatoes more sand gravel sand
sand this isn't even what i'm using for
the pickle shop this is just for this
base all the pickle stuff is already
over there i've picked out a little
place and i'm ready but the first thing
that we need is loads of pickles we
actually need to go and get ourselves
plenty of pickles and i think i have a
pretty decent way of doing that we're
gonna do a quick architect delivery oh
and by the way the name is now
officially the architects or just
architects because
the overwhelming vote was
not for buildstone it was like 80
for architects so people obviously like
that one a lot more so i'm going to do a
quick delivery for mumbo so you need
some packed ice and us architect guys we
stick together even though we haven't
really worked out what we're doing yet
we're still trying to just form our
bases
we still help each other out so i'm
gonna go and deliver him a lot of packed
ice
there he is i should give you that and
well i guess i'll be off then
well there we go that is the delivery
done he's got packed ice uh he'll i
guess we'll just use what he needs right
let's go and build this pickle farm
because we've been putting this off now
and i think i'm finally ready so i've
been trying to find a spot look at how
much this has evolved since we started
seriously it's really packed and you
can't build a pickle farm right in the
middle of it all this is busy this is
busy so i've chosen a bit off to the
side
i don't know actually if that is part of
the shopping district everything seems
to be
totally in here so i'm just gonna
squeeze it in
over here between the log thing and the
rocket shop but i don't really want to
be down here in this little crevice here
what i want to do is make my own little
island one island my own little hill so
i can put the jar on the top so it pokes
over this building and you'll be able to
see it much like this one so i think
i've got enough of what i need to do
that but we actually we actually need
some pickles i i haven't actually got
that many to sell so we're gonna make a
quick machine that i think will work
i don't think i can be bothered to make
a farm
right now so i'm just gonna do a really
quick way of getting some pickles just
to initially stock it and then i'm gonna
find a way of automating this process
even better but right now i just need to
get my hands on plenty of pickles so
what i'm going to do is just make a
quick very quick platform of coral
blocks so i can remove this later on so
if you don't know
pickles have to be placed i haven't got
any pickles where are my pickles so
if you don't know pickles have to be
placed on coral blocks i place the
pickle and then i can bone meal until it
spreads everywhere that it needs to go
eventually it will just stop so i can
just collect all these
place another lot bone meal bone meal
bone meal without trying to hit it and
then i can just harvest the pickles
really quickly
okay
that's i mean the sun's going down
that's definitely a sign that we've done
enough pickles for now
i'm proper sick of collecting these now
i did it the very very long way
i think i have an idea to make a super
over complicated pickle farm but i might
need to ask mumbo for his help on making
one of these
but for now
i'm just gonna stock it manually because
we haven't even made the shop yet that's
what we need to do now we need to
actually make the shop that's that's
probably enough pickles right i mean how
many pickles do people need
that i can i can spread it out and make
make it look like i've got loads right
okay
let's get started on making this hill
i have spent
way longer on this than i thought so
the time lapse is just finished but i
mainly just showed the big giant pickle
jar and it looks like a bit of a mess
i'm hoping when i put some water in it
you'll be able to separate each one
but
i'm green so
i went that little bit further
so underneath
i turned myself into a pickle guys
i spent hours and i mean hours
just
getting rid of all of this oh
so that i could create a giant inverted
pickle
with my face on it
i i don't really know why i did this
because this entire space really isn't
useful i guess it's just for the joke of
it all
so what i'm going to do now is quickly
make a way to get up so inside the jar
is where i'm going to be selling the
pickles
but i need to create a way to get up and
down on this
so
the best way is a water elevator and i'm
basically going to use the little trick
that i did at the start with the
aquarium
so what i'm going to do
i think
is i need to create a 3x3
now in theory
in theory the water should then fall
down from here land in this
and nothing should go wrong
in theory now i don't actually have a
much better way of getting out of here
yet other than just using the elite
trend taking a bit of damage so let's go
for it
oh
oh yep made it
[Laughter]
balancing between the walls okay
let's give this a shot shall we
and it hasn't caused any issues
so we've done it we've we've properly
managed to do it and it works on both
sides now we just need to see what this
looks like from here
you can still see my face it definitely
is lighting up
this is not as
majestic as i perhaps thought because
one pillar see okay here's the problem
you can't make a single pillar
with the soul sand and the magma block
it just it doesn't work like that you've
got
you've got to make it so that there's a
surrounding bit which is really sucky
it doesn't look good at all really
doesn't there might be a better way of
doing this there might be a better way
of doing this
because what i could do
well it's a good prototype but i think i
have a better idea no
no
oh
there we go oh that is so much better oh
my goodness i didn't realize quite how
chunky a three by three
water
elevator would be so definitely
definitely the right way to go was some
stained glass made out of green so and
it doesn't really affect the pickle too
much you can still see the pickle shape
it still works i just need to light it
up a bit better that's all
okay i think this is the main bit done
the pickle bit so this is how you get up
and down and
i've actually thought of a bit of a
devious plan but first
we've got to fill in the jar of pickles
with water
so the first thing is to cover this up
and now we just need to get some buckets
looks like we're completely full now no
gaps of air
oh my goodness that took so long maybe i
needed more than three buckets but it
worked out in the end it definitely
worked out in the end
oh bail bail bail bail
no no no
oh i'm so sick of these things
okay
i'm ready to actually start
doing
i'm actually ready to start stocking
this up now i'm very excited this is my
very first shop it had to be sea pickles
of course but now because i've done this
i've got to add in some signs hey guys i
turn myself into a pickle jump on in
all right so they see that sign they say
i've turned myself into a pickle now
here's the joke okay i will change this
in the future but you know me i'm a
mischievous man
and i'm going to make it so that there's
no easy way out
oh no there's a block missing i can fix
that from the outside okay anyway so we
go inside you've got to jump in
and sink down
and then i'm going to leave another sign
well
you seem to be in a bit of a pickle
i mean this shop is ninety percent puns
ninety percent puns ten percent selling
pickles i think i've actually created a
hell zone okay so the only way out at
the moment is to fly out via elite so
you're stuck in here all right so going
to head on up to the shop it's a pretty
big deal
i'm gonna oh you're gonna hate me after
this
everyone's gonna hate me after this
i don't know when it's ever gonna end do
not touch they are picklish
i i should actually stock up the shop
before i continue with this signage so
you come up here and you see all of
these pickles
pickle up
okay pickle up as many pickles as you
need one diamond equals two stacks
hopefully that's a good amount
for what i'm going i haven't actually
got that much stock but it should be
enough to make a small profit
so far
do not touch they are picklish i need to
come up with a few more pickle puns and
then i'll be happy and then there's
pickles all over these pickles pickles
pickles pickles pickles pickles pickles
i don't think i'm ever going to get sick
of that and there's actually no way out
that's part of the joke of this it is a
pun the whole shop is called in a pickle
so you come in here you buy your pickles
you're in a jar there's no way out so
you come here and then you go down here
and then you when you realize
that you're actually stuck it's too late
you read this sign again and it says
well you seem to be in a bit of a pickle
oh this is absolutely brilliant devious
and well dare i say it genius but we
should probably make it so there's a
safe way down there's no point in
assuming that everyone has an elytra so
we should create a little bit of a safe
way down how does this look from the
outside now that's lit up it makes no
difference whatsoever whether it's lit
up or not that's probably the biggest
disappointment about 1.13 is that
even when you have water behind glass
it's still not particularly visible and
it's really annoying okay so you arrive
it says hey guys i turned myself into a
pickle jump on in oh this is so cool
this is so brilliant my pickle pun
ability is running out i've added a few
some of them are a little bit sketchy
okay so this is what i've got don't
touch they are picklish this water can
be a little cumbersome get it cucumber
buy more pickles it's a pretty sweet
deal
and then right up here if they're
looking for more
there's
being stuck in here must be jarring get
it cause we're in a jar oh and never a
dill moment in this shop
okay i'm done i'm done that's enough we
have officially finished the first shop
the worst shop ever made and also
possibly the best shop ever made
oh my goodness
oh so they're in a bit of a pickle i
should probably actually
make a way out to be honest but
maybe not now maybe once everyone's had
a little visit to the shop and had their
little laugh and trying to figure a way
out then then then i'll add a way out
properly but for now this is my little
prank my little joke this is a very
elaborate prank and i should actually be
starting my own base i should be doing
my own base why am i here
that is gonna trigger a lot of people so
that's the last thing we're gonna fix
before
it's over we finished our very first
shop now we just have to wait to make a
little bit of money and then i can tick
that off of my bucket list i'm
definitely looking forward to seeing
people's reactions to this it's going to
be so funny to see them one come and see
my face well they'll they'll read the
sign
jump on in so they jump on in if they
haven't got any lighter then they can
just fall in the water you seem to be in
a bit of a pickle which they are and
then they go on up it's a pretty big
deal
oh this is just gonna be brilliant i
can't wait to see people's reactions and
then hopefully they buy some pickles as
well
they read all the puns they have a swim
around and then they go back down
just to realize
that they can't get out
and then they read the sign and then
they understand what this means all
together absolutely brilliant
anyway that's it for me everyone thank
you very much for watching
i hope you enjoyed this episode i hope
you enjoyed watching
us make
a horrible funny
cranky
shot a big jar of pickles
and i will see you in the next
hermitcraft episode where hopefully
we will make some serious progress
and put a dent in building this base
thanks everyone for watching
and good
bye